A Finding Aid to the Lee Nordness business records and papers, circa 1931-1992 (bulk 1954-1984), in the Archives of American Art AAA.nordlee
Archives of American Art
- Nordness Gallery, Inc. and Lee Nordness Galleries Art Advisory Section, Inc., bulk 1958-1982; circa 1938-1992; Series 1; 67.8 Linear feet Boxes 1-67, 117-119
  - Correspondence, 1950-1992; 1.1
    - Newsletter, 1962, undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Nordness Gallery, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Nordness Gallery, 1960-1964 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - Mary Nye Gallery, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Obelisk Gallery, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - O'Connor, Thomas, 1962-1964 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Overs, Gair, 1969-1973 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Pakistan Arts Council, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Patumwan Gallery, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Pending Trip, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Penthouse Gallery, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
    - The Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1965-1968 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - The Phillips Exeter Academy, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Photographs, 1960-1963 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Photographs to Reorder, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Les Arts Plastiques Modernes, 1966-1968 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Publications, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Publicity, 1960-1963 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Galerie Jacqueline Ranson, 1966-1968 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Ratcliffe, Mary, 1967-1970 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Esther-Robles Gallery, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Sara Roby Foundation, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Ross, Ann, 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Rowan Gallery, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Royal Academy of Arts, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - S.E. Rubenstein and Associates, 1961-1964 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Safrai Art Gallery, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - St. Armands Gallery, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 28-29)
    - Saltzman Melchner & Co., 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - San Francisco, 1958-1962 (Box 8, Folder 31-32)
    - Seattle Art Museum, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Seligman Gallery, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Sell, George, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Shannon, Alice, circa 1974 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Show Requests, 1970-1975 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Shows Out of Gallery, 1964-1968 (Box 8, Folder 38-39)
    - Signs, 1959-1963 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Sindelir Gallery, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Skowhegan School, 1963-1969 (Box 8, Folder 42-44)
    - Slide Shows, 1980s (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Smithsonian Institution National Collection of Fine Arts, 1964-1968 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Sottsass, Ettore, 1980s (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Spanish International Pavilion, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Stewart, Ronald, circa 1960s (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Storleer, Ola, 1968-1973 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Szabo, George, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Tamarind Lithography Workshop Facts, circa 1964 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Teacher-Student Exhibition, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Tennessee Fine Arts Center, 1968; 1966 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Terrace Galleries, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Time, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - To Be Filed, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 57-58)
    - Traveling Shows, 1987-1990 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Tripp/Bridge Club, 1970-1973 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Turner, Philip, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Underhill, William, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - United States Information Agency (USIA), 1967 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Unpaid Accounts, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Vanderborght, M.S., 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Peter Vanderborght Gallery, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Verle Gallery, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Viking Press, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - Wanamakers, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Ward, Jacqueline, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - Whistler Letters of Authenticity, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - Willow Press, 1966-1968 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - The Wisconsin Union, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Gordon Woodside Galleries, 1964-1967 (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - Works From Collectors To Be Sold, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Works Offered For Sale, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - World's Fair, 1960-1964 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Yamada Art Gallery, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Yoseido Gallery, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - Zinn's Framers, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - Restricted Folder, 1977 (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Artist's Files, bulk 1968-1982; circa 1938-1985; 1.2; 10.35 Linear feet Boxes 9-19, 117
    Folders are arranged alphabetically by artist's last name.
    Artist's Files contains documentation regarding Nordness' permanent roster of artists and many other artists with whom Nordness dealt for various projects, especially Objects:USA and Circle of Arts/Objects. Materials include correspondence with artists, galleries, and museums regarding sales, loans, and consignments; artist's biographies; exhibition printed materials; clippings; and scattered photographs. Artists found here overlap with those in other series and subseries, and contain related materials. Researchers are encouraged to consult other series regarding particular artists.
    - Agerholm, Jane and Gunnar, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Akers, Adela, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Albers, Annie, 1977; 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Al-Hilali, Neda, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Amaral, Olga de, 1981-1984 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Ames, Arthur, 1966; 1968-1969; 1955 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Apodaca, Joe Reyes, 1968-1973 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
    - Appleton, Rachel, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Arneson, Robert, 1964-1973 (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
    - Aronson, David, 1959-1968 (Box 9, Folder 12-16)
    - Autio, Rudy, 1968-1969; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Bacerra, Ralph, 1969-1972 (Box 9, Folder 18-19)
    - Bailey, Clayton, 1982; 1969-1975 (Box 9, Folder 20-21)
    - Ball, F. Carlton, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Bambas, Thomas, 1968-1977 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Bates, Kenneth, 1969-1972; 1977 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Bauer, Fred and Patti, 1968-1971; 1985 (Box 9, Folder 25-26)
    - Bauer, Patti, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Bechtle, Robert, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Belfer, Nancy, 1968-1970 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Billeci, Andre, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Bitar, Helen, 1968-1973; 1979-1982 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Blaustein, Al, 1957-1968 (Box 9, Folder 32-35)
    - Blumenau, Lili, 1965-1969 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Blunk, J.B., 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Bornt, Janice, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Brandt, Michael, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Brown, Charlie, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Brynner, Irena, 1968-1973 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Burgess, Anna K., 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Burn, Stephanie, 1970; 1972 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Cabot, Rose, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Canavier, Elena, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Carpenter, Arthur Espenet, 1972-1973; 1968 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Cartwright, Roy, 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Castle, Wendell, 1970-1985; 1965 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Chamberlain, Elwyn, 1960-1963 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Chihuly, Dale, 1968-1972; 1981 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Christensen, Hans, 1969-1972 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Clayden, Marion, 1968-1974 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Coffey, Michael, 1971-1975 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Cohen, Ahza, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Cohen, Michael and Harriet, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Coleman, Thomas L., 1972-1975 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Collie, Alberto, 1963-1968 (Box 10, Folder 18-21)
    - Conover, Claude, 1968-1971 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Cory, Ken, 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Craver, Margaret, 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Crawford, Ralston, 1961-1965 (Box 10, Folder 25-27)
    - Creitz, William, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Crumrine, Jim, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Cushing, Val, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Daly, Stephen, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - D'Arista, Robert, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Davis, Ruth, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - De Staebler, Stephen, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - De Vore, Richard, 1969; 1983 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Doner, Michele Oka, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - DiMare, Dominic, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Dreisbach, Carl Fritz, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Duckworth, Ruth, 1982; 1969 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Dudchenko, Boris, 1968-1971 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Earl, Jack, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Eikerman, Alma, 1977; 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Elliott, Lillian, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Engle, Barbara, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Engle, Robert, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Esherick, Wharton, 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Eshkanian, Ruben, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Fannin, Allen and Dorothy, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Farrell, Bill, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Felton, Frances, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Fenster, Fred, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Ferguson, Ken, 1968-1973 (Box 11, Folder 4-5)
    - Fike, Philip, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Fisch, Arline, 1969-1975 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Fishback, Kurt, 1968-1974; 1982; 1984 (Box 11, Folder 8-9)
    - Fletcher, Sally, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Fowler, Marilyn, 1970-1974; 1981 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Frimkess, Mike, 1968-1977 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Fritsch, John, 1965-1968 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Fritz, Robert C., 1969 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Funai, Carol, 1968-1974 (Box 11, Folder 15-16)
    - Funk, Vern, 1968-1970 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Gibran, Kahlil, 1961-1965 (Box 11, Folder 18-20)
    - Gieling, Imogene B., 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Gikow, Ruth, 1964-1966 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Gilhooly, David, 1968-1973 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Glick, John Parker, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Goo, Gwen-Lin, 1969-1970; 1977-1979 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Griffiths, William, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Grippe, Peter, 1960-1967 (Box 11, Folder 27-30)
    - Gronborg, Erik, 1968-1974; 1981 (Box 11, Folder 31-32)
    - Grotell, Maija, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Gruber, Aaronel de Roy, 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Guermonprez, Trude, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Guglielmi, Louis, 1958-1968 (Box 11, Folder 36-38)
    - Hallman, Ted, 1980; 1968 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Harper, William, 1972-1975 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Harvey, Virginia, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Heaton, Maurice, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Hebald, Milton, 1958-1969 (Box 11, Folder 43-45)
    - Hebald, Milton, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Heimovics, Marilyn, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Helwig, H.B., 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Hicks, Sheila, 1968-1972 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Higby, Wayne, 1968-1973 (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
    - Higgins, Frances and Michael, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Hilton, Eric, 1978-1979 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Hirsche, H. Lee, 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Hopper, David G., 1969-1971 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Horiuchi, Paul, 1962-1972 (Box 12, Folder 11-12)
    - Horiuchi, Tzivia, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Hornby, Anne, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Hui Ka-Kwong, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Hultberg, Peter, 1968-1972 (Box 12, Folder 16-17)
    - Illes, Terry, 1968-1969; 1981 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Ipsen, Kent, 1969-1974 (Box 12, Folder 19-20)
    - Jefferson, Bob, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Jennerjahn, Elizabeth, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Jerry, Michael, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Johnson, Gilbert, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Jurs, Nancy, 1969-1972 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Kachadoorian, Zubel, 1959-1968 (Box 12, Folder 26-30)
    - Kaltenbach, Steve, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Kaneko, Jun, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Karnes, Karen, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Kasuba, Aleksandra, 1969-1974 (Box 12, Folder 34-35)
    - Kaufman, Glen, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Kearns, James, 1963-1965 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Kelly, Marie T., 1968-1969; 1975-1982 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Kemenyffy, Steven, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Kennedy, Michael, 1981-1983 (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Keyser, William A., 1969 (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - King, Robert, 1968-1970 (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - Kington, Brent, 1977-1978; 1968-1970 (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Klein, Jody, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - Koblick, Freda, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - Koos, Vivian, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Kottler, Howard, 1968-1974 (Box 12, Folder 47-48)
    - Krank, Wolfram, 1968-1970; 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Kretsinger, Mary, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Krevitsky, Nik, 1969-1971 (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - Kriegman, Carolyn, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 52)
    - Kuemmerlein, Janet, 1968-1970; 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - Kuwahara, Naoko, 1968-1969; 1977 (Box 12, Folder 54)
    - Labino, Dominick, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Lane, Doyle, 1965-1972 (Box 12, Folder 56-57)
    - Lang, Rodger, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 58)
    - Langlet, Ragnhild, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 59)
    - Lardera, Berto, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 60)
    - Larsen, Jack Lenor, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 61)
    - La Verdiere, Bruno, 1968-1969; 1982 (Box 12, Folder 62)
    - Lebrun, Rico, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Lechtzin, Stanley, 1965-1973 (Box 13, Folder 2-3)
    - Leedy, James, 1979; 1968-1971 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Lennard, John, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Lesch, Alma, 1968-1972 (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
    - Levi, Julian, 1957-1968 (Box 13, Folder 8-13)
    - Liebes, Dorothy, circa 1968-1977 (Box 13, Folder 14-15)
    - Lipofsky, Marvin B., 1968-1973; 1981 (Box 13, Folder 16-17)
    - Littleton, Harvey, 1968-1975; 1982-1985 (Box 13, Folder 18-19)
    - Loeber, Ken, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Loloma, Charles, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Loloma, Otellie, 1977; 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Long, Susan, 1967-1969 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Lovell-Cooper, Sylvia, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Lucero, Fred, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Lynn, Thomas, 1968-1969; 1981 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Maldonado, Adál, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Maloof, Sam, 1982; 1976; 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Marcus, Fred, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Markusen, Tom, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Marquis, Richard, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Marshall, John, 1968-1971 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Martin, Bill, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Martinez, Maria, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Mason, John, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - McCormick, Patrick, 1968-1975; 1981 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - McCutchen, Earl, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - McGlauchlin, Tom, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - McIlvane, Ed, 1980-1982; 1973 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - McIntosh, Harrison, 1983; 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - McKinley, Donald, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Meigs, Walter, 1957-1965 (Box 13, Folder 42-45)
    - Meigs, Walter, 1965-1968 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Melchert, James, 1968-1970 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Meredith, Dorothy, 1968-1971 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Michaels, Glen, 1968-1969 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Miller, Frederick A., 1968-1969 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Miller, John Paul, 1982; 1968-1969 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Millman, Edward, 1957-1959 (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
    - Moore, Hellyn, 1966-1970 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Moty, Joyce, 1972-1974 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Myers, Joel Philip, 1968-1970 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Nagle, Ron, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Nakashima, George, 1968-1970 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Natale, John, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Natzler, Gertrud and Otto, 1950s-1983 (Box 14, Folder 15-17)
    - Nelson, Paul, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - New Holy, Sophie, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Newcomb, Kim, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Ng, Win, 1968-1969; 1964 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Nohr, Harry, 1967-1970 (Box 14, Folder 22-23)
    - Nottingham, Walter, 1968-1978 (Box 14, Folder 24-25)
    - Osgood, Jere, 1968-1972 (Box 14, Folder 26-27)
    - Oxtoby, David, 1964-1968 (Box 14, Folder 28-29)
    - Painter, Hal, 1968-1969 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Paley, Albert, 1971-1975; 1981 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Papenthien, Ruth Mary, 1968-circa 1974 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Pappas, George, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Pappas, Marilyn R., 1968-1971 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Paque, Jean Michaels, 1968-1970 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Parrott, Alice Kagawa, 1968-1970 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Pattison, Abbott, 1957-1960 (Box 14, Folder 37-39)
    - Pearson, Ronald, 1968-1976 (Box 14, Folder 40-41)
    - Peck, Lee B., 1968-1969 (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - Peiser, Mark C., 1969 (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Pereira, Irene Rice, 1953-1961 (Box 14, Folder 44-45)
    - Pereira, Irene Rice, 1959-1962 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
    - Philips, Mary Walker, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Poor, Henry Varnum, circa 1968-1970 (Box 15, Folder 4-5)
    - Prestopino, Gregorio, 1958-1967 (Box 15, Folder 6-11)
    - Price, Kenneth, 1968-1970 (Box 15, Folder 12-13)
    - Prip, John, 1968-1972 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Pugliese, Joseph, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Radakovitch, Svetozar, 1968-1973; 1979-1980 (Box 15, Folder 16-17)
    - Reade, Dorothy, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Reitz, Donald, 1968-1973 (Box 15, Folder 19-20)
    - Renk, Merry, 1968-1983 (Box 15, Folder 21-22)
    - Mary Remy Revor, Sister, 1968-1973 (Box 15, Folder 23-24)
    - Rhodes, Daniel, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Rice, Jacquelyn, 1972-1974 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Roach, Ruth, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Rockwell, Peter, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Rohde, Lee M., 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Rose, Francis, circa 1938-1960 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Rossbach, Ed, 1974; 1968-1970 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Saco, Don, 1963; 1967 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Saito, Kiyoshi, circa 1961-1965 (Box 15, Folder 33-34)
    - Sanders, Herb, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Sanderson, Ormand, 1969-1971 (Box 15, Folder 36-37)
    - Sax, Bill, 1968-1974 (Box 15, Folder 38-39)
    - Scheier, Edwin and Mary, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 40-41)
    - Schlanger, Jeff, 1979-1980; 1969 (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - Schoenfeld, Laure, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 43)
    - Schwarcz, June, 1979; 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 44)
    - Sekimachi, Kay, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 45)
    - Sell, George, 1972-1981 (Box 15, Folder 46)
    - Senungetuk, Ronald, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 47)
    - Shannon, Alice, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 48)
    - Shaw, Richard, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 49)
    - Shira, Cynthia, 1969-1971 (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - Shores, Ken, 1968-1972 (Box 15, Folder 51)
    - Siler, Patrick, 1968-1972 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Simpson, Tom, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Sipantzi, Zaven Zee, 1969-1973 (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
    - Siporin, Mitchell, 1957-1962 (Box 16, Folder 6-7)
    - Skoogfors, Olaf, 1968-1969; 1979 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Smith, Arthur, 1968; 1972 (Box 16, Folder 9-10)
    - Solberg, Ramona, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Soldner, Paul, 1969; 1982-1983 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Soleri, Paulo, 1968-1973 (Box 16, Folder 13-14)
    - Soles, Michael, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Someroski, James M., 1969 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Sowers, Robert, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Sperry, Robert, 1977-1985; 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Spinski, Victor, 1970-1973 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Staffel, Rudolph, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Stalnaker, Budd, 1968-1971 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Stamsta, Jean, 1978; 1968-1973 (Box 16, Folder 22-23)
    - Stearns, Thomas, 1977-1978; 1969 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Stehman, Polly, 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Stephens, Curtis, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Stephenson, John, 1977-1978; 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Stocksdale, Bob, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Stockton, Ann, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Stone, Gilbert, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Striui, Robert, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Struck, Jack, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Stull, Robert, 1983; 1969 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Sumers, Martin, 1962-1965 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Takaezu, Toshiko, 1968-1973; 1965; 1978-1983 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Takemoto, Henry, 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Tanner, James, 1968-1969; 1978-1984 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Tawney, Lenore, 1968-1970; 1977 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Temple, Byron, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Thrall, Arthur, 1964-1968 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - Timock, George P., 1982; 1969 (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Turner, Robert, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Underhill, William, 1985; 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Unterseher, Chris, 1968-1970 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - Utermohlen, William, 1966-1968 (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - Valenza, Daniel, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 46)
    - Vandenberg, Peter, 1969-1972 (Box 16, Folder 47)
    - Van Manen, Mathys Teunissen, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 48)
    - Vaughan, Michael, 1960s (Box 16, Folder 49)
    - Voulkos, Peter, 1968-1974 (Box 16, Folder 50-51)
    - Wallace, Jerome, 1977-1985; 1969 (Box 16, Folder 52)
    - Washington, James, Jr., 1957-1964; 1968 (Box 16, Folder 53)
    - Watson, Lynda, 1969-1970; 1979 (Box 16, Folder 54)
    - Wayne, James, 1969-1971 (Box 16, Folder 55)
    - Weinrib, David, 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 56)
    - Weitzman, Susan, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 57)
    - Wells, George, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 58)
    - Westphal, Katherine, 1968-1969; 1980 (Box 16, Folder 59)
    - Whistler, James McNeill, 1963-1967 (Box 16, Folder 60-61)
    - Whistler, James McNeill, circa 1968 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Widenhofer, Allan, 1968; 1979 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Wiener, Ed, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Wiener, Sam, 1968-1971; 1977 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Wilde, John, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Wildenhain, Frans, 1969-1972; 1963 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Wildenhain, Marguerite, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Wilhelmi, William, 1971-1973 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Williams, Berry, 1968-1972 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Williams, Hiram, 1961-1983 (Box 17, Folder 10-20)
    - Wilson, Laurie, 1972-1973 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Winokur, Robert, 1972-1973 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Winston, Bob, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Woell, J. Fred, 1968-1973 (Box 17, Folder 24-25)
    - Wood, Beatrice, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Woolley, Ellamarie and Jackson, 1968-1973 (Box 17, Folder 27-28)
    - Wright, G. Alan, 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Wyman, William, 1977-1985; 1970-1973 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Yamada, Shige, 1969-1975 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Young, David, 1975-1976 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Zachai, Dorian, 1969-1973; 1979 (Box 17, Folder 33-34)
    - Zeidman, Robert, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - Zeisler, Claire, 1968-1969 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Zerbe, Karl, 1957-1980s (Box 18, Folder 2-15)
    - Znamierowski, Nell, 1968-1969 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Other Artists, 1958-1968 (Box 18, Folder 17-21)
    - Other Artists, Miscellaneous Materials, 1967-1974 (Box 19, Folder 1-4)
    - Restricted Folder, circa 1968-1969 (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - Project Files, 1952-1990; 1.3
    This subseries houses records pertaining to large scale projects, including Art:USA: The Johnson Collection of Contemporary American Painting and the accompanying tour, Art:USA:NOW; Objects: USA Johnson Contemporary Crafts Art Collection; Circle of Art/Objects, a fine crafts direct mail and sales venture, and the accompanying travelling exhibition, Art/Objects:USA; a craft fair and MANtransFORMS, the opening exhibition of Cooper-Hewitt, National Museum of Design; the international art collection for Council House, a lodging facility at the Johnson Wax Wind Project Conference Center; the art collection for Metromedia, Inc. (Mr. X); and various other smaller projects and project proposals.